[
  {
    "answer": "array",
    "question": "an index-numbered list that can hold more than one value at a time"
  },
  {
    "answer": "iteration",
    "question": "the repetition of a sequence of instructions a specified number of times or until a condition is met"
  },
  {
    "answer": "iterate through an array",
    "question": "accessing each element of an array one by one"
  },
  {
    "answer": "for each loop",
    "question": "a control flow statement that allows you to access every item in an iterable collection (an array, a string, etc.) one at a time"
  },
  {
    "answer": "input validation",
    "question": "the testing of any data supplied to the app by a user, external file, or other external source."
  },
  {
    "answer": "try/except",
    "question": "defines a block of code to be tested for errors while it is being executed. Prevents the app from crashing due to errors in input or other unforeseeable things"
  },
  {
    "answer": "conditional",
    "question": "a control flow structure that performs different actions depending on whether a specific Boolean statement evaluates to true or false"
  },
  {
    "answer": "function",
    "question": "A set of instructions that performs a specific task separately from a main script and returns to the main script when it is complete. A block of named, reusable code that is used to perform a single, related action"
  },
  {
    "answer": "pre-conditional loop",
    "question": "a loop in which the condition is tested before the body is executed. The body of the while loop will NOT happen if this condition is false."
  },
  {
    "answer": "post-conditional loop",
    "question": "a loop in which the body is executed before the condition is ever tested. For example, in a 'do while' loop the body will ALWAYS run one or more times"
  },
  {
    "answer": "pseudocode",
    "question": "a human-readable description of what a computer program or algorithm will do. Usually written as comments."
  },



  {
    "answer": "big data",
    "question": "a broad term for datasets so large or complex that traditional data processing applications are inadequate"
  },
  {
    "answer": "Moore's Law",
    "question": "a prediction made by Gordon Moore in 1965 that computing power will double every 1.5-2 years, it has remained more or less true ever since"
  },
  {
    "answer": "trend",
    "question": "a line indicating the general course or tendency of some data, such as a set of points on a graph"
  },
  {
    "answer": "data breach",
    "question": "a security incident in which private information is accessed without authorization"
  },
  {
    "answer": "Caesar cipher",
    "question": "a technique for encryption that shifts the alphabet by some number of characters"
  },
  {
    "answer": "cipher",
    "question": "the generic term for a technique (or algorithm) that performs encryption"
  },
  {
    "answer": "cracking encryption",
    "question": "When you attempt to decode a secret message without knowing all the specifics of the cipher"
  },
  {
    "answer": "decryption",
    "question": "a process that reverses encryption, taking a secret message and reproducing the original plain text"
  },
  {
    "answer": "encryption",
    "question": "a process of encoding messages to keep them secret, so only 'authorized' parties can read it."
  },
  {
    "answer": "random substitution cipher",
    "question": "an encryption technique that maps each letter of the alphabet to a randomly chosen other letters of the alphabet."
  },
  {
    "answer": "computationally hard",
    "question": "a problem for a computer in which it cannot arrive at a solution in a reasonable amount of time"
  },
  {
    "answer": "asymmetric encryption",
    "question": "used in public key encryption, it is a scheme in which the key to encrypt data is different from the key to decrypt."
  },
  {
    "answer": "modulo",
    "question": "a mathematical operation that returns the remainder after integer division."
  },
  {
    "answer": "private key",
    "question": "In an asymmetric encryption scheme the decryption key is kept private and never shared, so only the intended recipient has the ability to decrypt a message that has been encrypted with a public key."
  },
  {
    "answer": "public key encryption",
    "question": "Used commonly on the web, it allows for secure messages to be sent between parties without having to agree on, or share, a secret key. It uses an asymmetric encryption scheme in which the encryption key is made public, but the decryption key is kept private."
  },
  {
    "answer": "symmetric encryption",
    "question": "an encryption scheme in which the key used to encrypt data is also used to decrypt"
  },



  {
    "answer": "logical operators",
    "question": "extra qualifications that can be added to a conditional. For example:  AND, OR, NOT"
  },
  {
    "answer": "two-dimensional array",
    "question": "an array of arrays"
  },
  {
    "answer": "global variables",
    "question": "variables created outside of a function that can be used inside of a function without being passed as arguments"
  },
  {
    "answer": "runtime error",
    "question": "an error that occurs when Python understands what you are saying, but runs into trouble while following your instructions. For example, division by zero or an error with user input"
  },
  {
    "answer": "syntax error",
    "question": "an error that occurs when Python can't understand what you are saying, because you've broken the rules of the language. For example, unexpected indent or cannot concatenate 'str' and 'int' objects"
  },
  {
    "answer": "while loop",
    "question": "a control flow structure that repeatedly executes its statements as long as the given pre-condition is true"
  },
  {
    "answer": "nested conditionals",
    "question": "an If Statement inside another If Statement"
  },
  {
    "answer": "dictionary",
    "question": "a collection of key and value pairs"
  },
  {
    "answer": "object",
    "question": "a collection of instance variables (data) and methods (getters/setters) that act on those instance variables"
  },



  {
    "answer": "bit",
    "question": "a column in the binary counting system with either a zero or a one. A Binary Digit."
  },
  {
    "answer": "byte",
    "question": "a unit of data that is made up of eight binary digits"
  },
  {
    "answer": "kilobyte",
    "question": "a unit of data that is made up of roughly one thousand (1,000) bytes"
  },
  {
    "answer": "megabyte",
    "question": "a unit of data that is made up of roughly one million (1,000,000) bytes"
  },
  {
    "answer": "gigabyte",
    "question": "a unit of data that is made up of roughly one billion (1,000,000,000) bytes"
  },
  {
    "answer": "lossy compression",
    "question": "an irreversible data reducing algorithm that uses inexact approximations, discarding some data to represent the content. Most commonly seen in image formats like jpg"
  },
  {
    "answer": "lossless compression",
    "question": "a data reducing algorithm that allows the original data to be perfectly reconstructed from the compressed data."
  },
  {
    "answer": "heuristic",
    "question": "a problem solving approach (algorithm) to find a satisfactory solution where finding an optimal or exact solution is impractical or impossible."
  },
  {
    "answer": "Huffman coding",
    "question": "a lossless compression algorithm that involves sorting characters from a set in order of their frequency."
  },
  {
    "answer": "metadata",
    "question": "data that describes other data. For example, a digital image may include data that describes the size of the image, number of colors, or resolution."
  },
  {
    "answer": "raster",
    "question": "an image made of a grid of pixels, also known as a bitmap image"
  },
  {
    "answer": "bitmap",
    "question": "an image made of a grid of pixels, also known as a raster image"
  },
  {
    "answer": "pixel",
    "question": "short for 'picture element', the fundamental unit of a digital image, typically a tiny square or dot that contains a single point of color of a larger image."
  },
  {
    "answer": "hexadecimal",
    "question": "A base-16 number system that uses sixteen distinct symbols 0-9 and A-F to represent numbers from 0 to 15"
  },
  {
    "answer": "RGB",
    "question": "a color model in which varying intensities of red, green, and blue light are added together in to reproduce a broad array of colors."
  },
  {
    "answer": "image resolution",
    "question": "the number of pixels in an image"
  },
  {
    "answer": "bit depth",
    "question": "the number of bits used to represent each pixel in an image. A measure of how many colors an image can store. For example, an 8-bit RGB image will actually have a total of 24-bits per pixel (8 for red, 8 for green, and 8 for blue)"
  }
]
